Finding Aid for the Livingston Gearhart Collection of Photographs, 1896-1969
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Additional receipts (2014), circa 1900-circa 1969, III.; Items 111-192
  - Livingston Gearhart seated at piano with some of his arrangements displayed, circa 1955, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Luedeke Studio (Buffalo, N.Y.) (Box 1, Item lg185)
  - Livingston Gearhart gesturing towards a music score with five student brass players, circa 1958, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg186)
  - Livingston Gearhart playing a celesta made by F. Sand & Co., circa 1958, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Marschall, Frederic, photographer (Box 1, Item lg187)
  - Livingston Gearhart playing a keyboard made by Arnold Dolmetsch, circa 1958, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Marschall, Frederic, photographer (Box 1, Item lg188)
  - Livingston Gearhart sitting at a keyboard made by Arnold Dolmetsch, circa 1958, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Marschall, Frederic, photographer (Box 1, Item lg189)
  - Livingston Gearhart laying without shirt outdoors, circa 1942, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Percival, Willa, 1916-2009 (Box 1, Item lg190)
  - Livingston Gearhart in profile with goatee, 1945, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg191)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing at a rehearsal of the University at Buffalo String Workshop, circa 1969, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg192)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Composers--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs; Gearhart, Livingston--Photographs; Waring, Virginia--Photographs; Waring, Fred, 1900-1984--Photographs; Boulanger, Nadia--Photographs; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974--Photographs; Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897--Photographs
Genres
Photographs
Associated Material
Bibliography
For information about Nadia Boulanger's classes, refer to:
Rosenstiel, Léonie. Nadia Boulanger: A Life in Music, W. W. Norton, 1982
For an English translation of the events regarding the weekend spent by Brahms in Krefeld, refer to:
Heinz von Beckerath's memoir in Brahms and his world, Rev. ed., Princeton University Press, 2009
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Livingston Gearhart Papers, 1933-1997,
Mus. Arc. 23.1
Finding aid for collection of prose writings, correspondence, programs, and clippings.
Livingston Gearhart Collection of Scores, 1930-1996
Mus. Arc. 23.2
Collection of manuscript and published scores composed or arranged by Livingston Gearhart. Also includes published scores of other composers as annotated by Gearhart.
Livingston Gearhart Recordings, 1949-2001
Mus. Arc. 23.4
Collection of 24 recordings, including compositions and arrangements by Livingston Gearhart, his memorial service, and the recordings of duo-pianists, Morley and Gearhart.
Pamela Gearhart Collection of Photographs, circa 1955-1983
Mus. Arc. 33.2
Collection of 207 photographs including images of Pamela Gearhart and casual snapshots of other musicians, including her husband Livingston Gearhart, Budapest String Quartet members Alexander and Mischa Schneider, and conductor Skitch Henderson. Also available as a digital collection in
University Libraries Digital Collections
.